So today, let's talk about boosting
autophagy with this one simple vitamin.
What is autophagy?
It's a condition in the body that
protects against cancer, infection,
neurodeeneration,
cardiovascular disease, aging. So in
your cells, you have this mechanism that
can clean up old damaged parts. Um, in a
cell, you have all these little parts.
You have your mitochondria. They're
called organels. They're part of the
little structures that form an assembly
line to make body tissue. All of those
individually can be recycled if they're
dysfunctional. So, autophagy is that
state where the body is breaking those
down and then turning them into raw
material to build new tissues. Also,
autophagy will help you clean up
infection, bacteria, viruses. So, it's
really, really important in the immune
system. And that vitamin that will
trigger autophagy is vitamin D. Vitamin
D regulates autophagy. So it's not just
about going on a long fast. It's also
about making sure you have enough
vitamin D in your body to allow this
process to work. There's something
called the vitamin D receptor. And if
that vitamin D receptor is impaired or
it's dysfunctional, that will limit your
capacity for autophagy because vitamin D
benefits parallel the autophagy
benefits. It's involved in um immune
system, autoimmune issues, um clearing
out TB, uh increasing cancer cell
apoptosis, which basically killing off
cancer cells. It's involving dropping
inflammation.
It decreases oxidative stress. It can
even prevent the mitochondria from
making too many oxidants. Uh those
things that cause oxidation. When you do
uh fasting like 18 hours or more, you
get this greater benefit of autophagy. U
but if you took vitamin D or you made
sure you had more sun, that would be a
very smart thing. And autophagy will
also clean up the damage from sunburn
and so will vitamin D. It's not the
vitamin D that caused the sunburn, it's
the UV damage on your skin. So if you
had sunburn, it you would see benefit
from taking vitamin D and going on a
fast. So the combination of those two
actions are very very important. So I
just wanted to bring up your awareness
of another thing that can help you
enhance autophagy. Thanks for watching.
So, if you're enjoying this content, go
ahead and share it with someone that
could really benefit from it.